CRAIG MASLOWSKI

Email: craig@craigmaslowski.com
Web: http://craigmaslowski.com

Summary

Over fourteen years of professional software engineering experience.

Experience leading development teams, including developers and business analysts.

Experience serving as technical project lead designing, developing, and architecting enterprise software solutions.

Experience with agile development, xtreme programming, and test driven development.

Eight years of experience with Microsoft .NET framework technologies including C#, ASP.NET (Web Forms and MVC), and .NET Framework 1.1-4.0.

Experience

Senior Software Engineer (Contract) Mitchell 1

November 2010 - Present

Worked on a team of five developers to create version 2 of www.repair-connect.net for truck repair shops to look up repair data based on engine control module trouble codes.

Enhanced the existing application to allow mechanics to find data by three additional code types.

Coded and tested all front end and middle tier changes utilizing existing application design patterns and prepared code to be incorporated into a service oriented architecture.

Technologies: C#, ASP.NET MVC, .Net Framework 3.5, SQL Server 2008, T-SQL, TDD, Javascript, jQuery, Ajax, Json, NUnit, NLogger, Visual Studio 2008/2010, Resharper, IIS, SVN, Team City, Version 1

Lead Software Engineer (Full Time) Active Network

July 2007 - August 2010

Worked on a team of eight developers to design and develop custom web based online registration system for youth team sports including an admin interface for client administrators to create team rosters, schedules, billing, and reporting.

Served as project technical lead performing duties including architecture of all new features and applications.

Architected improvements to existing codebase by introducing enterprise design patterns and test driven development (TDD).

Established coding standards and ensured the development team followed the standards set forth through code reviews and direct mentoring.

Technologies: C#, ASP.NET, VB.NET, .Net Framework 1.1-3.5, SQL Server 2005/2008, T-SQL, TDD, ASMX Web Services, Javascript, jQuery, MS Ajax, MS Test Suite, Visual Studio 2005/2008, IIS, SVN, Team City, Crucible, Jira

Lead Software Engineer (Full Time) GMAC - Rescap

June 1999 - January 2007

Acted as team and technical project lead on multiple projects.

Managed a team of three developer and one business analyst in support of an enterprise foreclosure accounting system.

Increased scalability of an enterprise foreclosure accounting system allowing it to handle an ever growing increases in loan volume.

Reduced support time required for foreclosure accounting system from 40 hours per month to 4 hours per month through bug fixes, optimizations, and architecture upgrades.

Improved departmental efficiency by implementing issue tracking standards and procedures for support and maintenance development. Administrated Footprints issue tracking system running on MS SQL Server.

Documented, designed, coded, tested, and supported web based software for reconciliation of cash flow in excess of 1 billion dollars per month as it moved through five enterprise systems.

Designed and developed system for tracking time and project/departmental billing for time spent by members of the development team.

Provided support and maintenance development for numerous data manipulation and analysis utilities.

Technologies: C#, ASP.NET, .Net Framework 1.1-2.0, SQL Server, T-SQL, Oracle, PL-SQL, VB6, C++, COM/COM+, MTS, MSMQ, MS Access, Crystal Reports, Visual Studio 6 & 2003-2005, Delphi, Footprints, Visual Source Safe

Software Engineer (Full Time) Media Services

June 1998 - June 1999

Developed custom accounting software for movie and television production companies following Generally Accepted Accounting Principles (GAAP)

Gathered requirements, documented design, and performed unit testing.

Technologies: Delphi, Paradox

Software Engineer (Full Time) GoldMine Software

May 1996 - June 1998

Designed and developed web based software to host technical knowledge base for use by end users and resellers.

Authored hundreds of articles for online support knowledge base.

Improved capabilities of the technical support department through design and development of numerous small utilities.

Technologies: Delphi, Dbase

Education General Education

California State University Fresno

Training Programming in C#

Seven Habits of Highly Effective People

Supervisory Certificate Program

Essential COM+ Programming in C++

Computer Electronic Technician Vocational Course

Learning Tree University

Franklin Covey

Learning Tree University

Developmentor UCLA Extension

Fresno Institute of Technology

References Available upon request.